[MUSIC]
[음악]
In this module, Emily covered various techniques for retrieving documents,
이 모듈에서 에밀리가 다양한 문서 검색 기법과
exploring representations for a data like word count and TFIDF.
단어수, TF-IDF와 같은 표현법을 탐구했습니다
Now we're gonna get a really cool Notebook where we put these ideas together and
이 개념을 하나로 합쳐서 노트북을 만들고
build a document retrieval system.
이를 통해 문서 검색 시스템을 구축해 봅시다
Using TFIDF.
TF-IDF를 써서요
So, let's go ahead and do just that.
곧바로 시작하죠
As usual, we're gonna be using Python Notebook and
평소와 같이 IPython 노트북을 쓸 텐데
in this one I'm gonna change the title to Document
여기서는 제목을 문서 검색으로 고칩니다
retrieval, and here we go.
됐죠
And again, as usual, I'm gonna hide the header.
또 평소와 같이 헤더를 감추고
And hide the toolbar to give us a little bit more space.
툴바를 감춰서 공간을 확보합니다
Okay, let's go ahead and fire up GraphLab Create.
이제 GraphLab Create을 띄우죠
So we're gonna do import graphlab
노트북에서 쓸 테니
since we're gonna be using it again in our notebook.
import graphlab으로 불러들입니다
Now the first step we're going to load some data.
제일 먼저 데이터 불러오기부터 하죠
So let's Load some text data.
텍스트 데이터 불러오기
This is interesting text data from Wikipedia,
위키피디아의 재밌는 텍스트 데이터인데요
and it's pages on people.
사람에 관한 페이지입니다
So, cool data set and I'm just going to load it, and
데이터 세트를 불러와서
we're going to see People which is gonna be an s frame
사람은 SFrame 오브젝트가 될 텐데
is gonna be graphlab.SFrame from a file and
graphlab.SFrame을 치고 파일이 필요한데
that file is called people wiki, right here.
파일은 people_wiki.gl입니다
And Here we go, we're loading it.
됐습니다  읽어왔고요
And the first thing that we're gonna do is just look at a few top lines of that file.
먼저 파일의 처음 몇 줄을 살펴보죠
So I'm just gonna go ahead and you should see we have,
바로 입력해서 보면
so this URI is basically the location of that page on Wikipedia.
URI는 페이지의 위치라고 생각하면 됩니다
This is the name of the person involved.
이건 사람 이름과
and the text of that page about that person.
그 사람에 대한 페이지 텍스트입니다
And you have this for a pretty nice number of people here.
꽤 많은 숫자의 사람이 있네요
So if you type len of people.
데이터 세트에서
In our data set.
사람이 몇 명인지 봅니다
And type enter you see that we are talking about 59,000 people in this data set.
엔터를 입력하면 59000명이 있네요
It's a pretty good set and
꽤 괜찮은 세트인데
you will see with DFIF we are going to do some really interesting documents.
TF-IDF로 굉장히 흥미로운 문서 검색을 하게 됩니다
Even in this relatively large data set.
데이터 세트가 상당히 크긴 하지만요
So the first thing we are going to do is just explore our data.
먼저 데이터를 탐색합니다
So let's #Explore the dataset and
#데이터 세트 탐색하기
checkout the text it contains.
어떤 텍스트가 들어있나 확인합니다
So let's start looking at a particular person dataset.
특정 인물 데이터 세트를 들여다보죠
And we're gonna look at the page for
현 미국 대통령인 바락 오바마의 페이지를
Barack Obama who is the current US President.
보도록 하죠
So out of this people s-frame I'm going to select the one whose name,
이 SFrame에서
so that's the name column, is equal
이름 열이
to Barack Obama.
바락 오바마인 인물을 찾습니다
And so I pressed enter, and I created this new variable called Obama.
엔터를 누르면 오바마란 새 변수가 생성되죠
And if you take a quick look at it, you see [COUGH] That it has the URL for
빠르게 훑어보면 오바마 페이지 URL,
the Obama page, the name Barack Obama, and the text for that page.
이름 바락 오바마, 페이지의 텍스트가 존재합니다
So let's dig in, and see what that text looks like.
텍스트가 어떤지 조금만 파보죠
So for Barack Obama, you'll see that
바락 오바마
Barack Hussein Obama was born on August 4th, 1961, and
바락 후세인 오바마는 1961년 8월 4일 태어났으며
is the 44th The current President of the United States.
미합중국의 제44대 대통령으로 재직 중이다
So pretty natural text will really expect for this kind of data.
이런 종류의 데이터에 있을법한 자연스러운 텍스트죠
So we can also look at some other personal data set.
다른 인물 데이터 세트도 보죠
So for example,
예를 들어 readLines 함수는 파일을
there's an actor called George Clooney who's been in a lot of movies.
많은 영화에 출연한 조지 클루니란 배우가 있습니다
So if you look at the people As frame we're gonna select,
SFrame에서 고르는데
so this is again a filter operation which we've been doing almost every network now.
노트북에서 매번 사용했던 필터를 이용하죠
Whose name is George Clooney?
이름은 조지 클루니
And then I'm just gonna go ahead and
그런 다음 조지 클루니의 텍스트를
show you the text that we get for George Clooney.
출력합니다
And you see that George Timothy Clooney was born in 1961.
조지 티모시 클루니는 1961년 출생입니다
So, basically, he's the same age as Barack Obama, but he's not president.
그러니까 바락 오바마와 같은 나이군요 대통령은 아니지만요
He's an American actor, writer.
조지 클루니는 미국의 배우, 작가,
Producer, director
프로듀서, 감독이자
and activist,
사회운동가이다
right here.
여기까지네요
[MUSIC]
[음악]